MARK WATSON

St Ives, NSW Australia 2075

0448 488 884

Email: mark@watsonised.com

Portfolio: https://hire.watsonised.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-watsonised/

GitHub: https://github.com/Mark33Mark

Summary

Full stack web developer with a property development and capital transactions background.

Has a deep understanding of electronics and programming using different languages and environments to deliver great user experiences. Past and current projects demonstrate creativity and an outstanding technical capability to develop meaningful applications for everyday use.

Completing a certificate in full stack development at the University of Sydney to further advance skills in developing responsive and accessible applications.

Highly capable developing in agile teams using git. Effectively delivers from well-articulated briefs or high level conceptual requests.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL

Applications: GitHub, mySQL, API

Tools: Express, React, Node, Handlebars, ¡Query, Moment, Inquirer, Bootstrap

Projects

Quot3d - mySQL database of quotes that randomly selects a quote for the user. Express and Nodejs used for the server side. Uploaded and hosted on Heroku platform.

Live app: https://quot3d.herokuapp.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/Mark33Mark/guoted

Weather Dashboard - API application that accesses the OpenWeather API for weather in locations around the world selected by the user. Includes a 7 day forecast and makes use of a graphical interface for improved user experience.

Live app: https://sun.watsonised.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/Mark33Mark/weather-dashboard

Lettuce eat - API application that accesses the Spoonacular API for recipes. Concept was around the user typing in the key ingredient and the application generates recipe ideas. Extensive user configuration provided.

Live app: https://eat.watsonised.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/Mark33Mark/recipe-generator

Experience

Watsonised Pty Ltd, Sydney NSW — Developer / Consultant

July 2019 - present

Privately owned company established for development services. The company is in a launch status until a sustainable client base is formed. Services include refactoring existing code, development of JavaScript applications and database development.

Accomplishments:

Developer and site administrator for Prospero's online presence. The site was developed using WordPress as the code base.

Website: https://prosperocommerce.com

Developed and built an internet of things (IoT) device for measuring room environment conditions including sensors for volatile organic compounds and dust. Using Arduino as the processor and connecting it to a remote database via wifi to upload sensor readings. A ground up development requiring industrial design, electronics and C-programming knowledge. The server side was coded to manage the client side data received to store in a mySQL database.

Website: https://watsonised.com/esp-data.php

Woolworths Group, Sydney NSW — Regional Development Manager

January 2012 - June 2019

Woolworths Group is the largest retail company in Australia by market capitalisation of approximately A\$45 billion.

Developed and implemented investment strategies for the expansion of the property business in NSW. Included board approval, identifying sites, negotiating their purchase, contracting to buy, lease negotiation, Council approval and construction. Directed teams of consultants including lawyers, project managers and design consultants. Demonstrated superior funds management capability with all projects being delivered under or on budget.

Accomplishments:

Wrote the board paper for approval to sell approximately 130 properties with a combined value of over \$200M and profit of \$20M over a 2 year period.

Acquired and developed approximately 20 properties for neighbourhood centres anchored by Woolworths' businesses.

EDUCATION

Coding Bootcamp Certificate - Full Stack Developer — *University of Sydney*

August 2021 - February 2022, Sydney NSW Australia

The Bootcamp education format compresses a number of topics into a six month program. The course focuses on technical programming skills in: GitHub, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript ES6+, Node, SQL, Heroku, Express and React.

Bachelor of Building Construction Management — *University of NSW*

Attained 1st class honours for a 5 year degree that included the successful completion of a thesis to satisfy requirements for graduation. Selected by the computer science lecturer to tutor the computer science stream of the course. Received the Multiplex prize for achieving the highest marks in the construction subjects over the five year course.